American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIe. 1845-1865 APS.Archives.IIe APS.Archives.IIe
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 27, 1854; 11x8-1/2; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Schrätter. 1p.,end.: F[raley] In German. Thanks for publications (Proceedings and Transactions).
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Jan. 1, 1855; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Ethnological Society of London
    A.L.S.: Richard Cull. 1p.,end.by F[isher]. Forwards publications through Henry Stevens to the APS and the Smithsonian.
  - Letter to ----, January 13, [1855]; 3 3/4" x 5 15/16"; Prescott, William Hickling, 1796-1859
    Boston, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses $5, in payment for A.P.S. Transactions, III.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 16, 1855; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of Scotland
    Edinburgh, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John Alex. Smith. 1p.,end.: J.L.LeC[onte]. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Obituary notice of Dr. Charles Caldwell, January 19, 1855; 6 1/4" x 7 3/4"; Coates, Benjamin Hornor, 1797-1881
    Philadelphia, 10pp. Dr.Com, Printed in Pro., VI. 77-80.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, January 20, 1855; 7 13/16" x 9 3/4"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to the presidency of the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 25, 1855; 10-1/4x8
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.H.Smyth. 1p.,end.: F[raley]. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 26, 1855; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: James Walker, Pres.and Thaddeus William Harris, Libn. 1p.,end.: F.F[raley] and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 27, 1855; 9-1/2x7-3/4; New York State Library
    Albany, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: T.Romeyn Beck. 1p.,end.: F[raley]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, Jan. 30, 1855; 10x7-3/4; Connecticut Historical Society
    Hartford, Printed L.filled in in ms S.: Chas. Hosmer. 1p.,end.: F[raley]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, Philadelphia, Feb. 1, 1855; 12x7-1/2; New Jersey Historical Society
    A.L.S.: Samuel H. Congar. 1p.,end. by J.L.LeC[onte]. Forwards publication.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the paper of Dr. Charles M. Wetherill on "Adipocire and its formation,", February 2, 1855; 8" x 10"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1p. and endorsement. D.S.: Franklin Bache, John F. Frazer, Robert Bridges. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 3, 1855; 9-3/4x7-3/4; American Antiquarian Society
    Worcester, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Sam[ue]l F. Haven. 1p.,end.: J.L.LeC[onte]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, February 5, 1855; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Darlington, William, 1782-1863
    Secretary of A.P.S., West Chester, 1 p. A.L.S. Encloses obituary notice of [William H.] Dillingham.
  - Obituary notice of Henry Reed, February 16, 1855; 8 1/4" x 13"; Frazer, John Fries, 1812-1872
    [Philadelphia], 7 pp. and endorsement. Dr.Com. Printed in A.P.S. Proceedings, VI, 87-91.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], Feb. 25, 1855; 10-1/2x8; St. Petersburg. Corp des ingénieurs des mines - État-major du
    St.Petersburg, Printed L.filled in in ms. 1p.,end.by J.L.LeC[onte]. In French. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to Ch[arle]s B. Trego, March 14, 1855; 8-1/2x7; Shurtleff, Nathaniel Bradstreet, 1810-1874
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p.,end.by F[isher]. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, March 15, 1855; 10-3/4x8-3/4; Akademie der Wissenschaften in Göttingen
    Göttingen, A.L.S.: Hausmann. 1p.,end.: E.O.K.[endall]. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, philadelphia, March 20, 1855; 11-1/2x9-1/2; Kaiserlich-Königliche Geographische Gesellschaft (Austria)
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.Haidinger. 1p.,end.by E.O.K[endall]. In German. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], April 5, 1855; 11x8-1/2; Hammer-Purgstall, Joseph, Frieherr von, 1774-1856
    Vienna, A.L.S. 1p.,end. by J.L.LeC[onte]. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 12, 1855; 10-1/2x8; Boston Society of Natural History
    Boston, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: S.L.Abbott. 1p.,end.: J.L.LeC[onte]. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 12, 1855; 10-1/4x8; Boston Society of Natural History
    Boston, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: S.L.Abbott. 1p.,end.: F[raley]. Thanks for proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, April 20, 1855; 9-1/2x6; Königlich Sächsische Gesellschaft der Wissenschaften zu Leipzig
    Leipzig, Printed L.filled in in ms. S.: G[ustav] Hartenstein. 1p.,end.by E.O.K[endall]. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Alex[ander] Dallas Bache, April 20, 1855; 8 3/16" x 10 9/16"; Patterson, Robert, 1743-1824
    President of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. A.N.S. Presents to the A.P.S. a portrait of Dr. Robert M. Patterson, its former president.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, April 20, 1855; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Société des sciences, de l'agriculture et des arts de Lille
    Lille, [read] Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.Chrestien. 2p.,end. by J.L.LeC[onte]. In French. Forwards publications and thanks for APS publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, May 1, 1855; 11x8-1/2; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wilhelm Braumüller. 1p.,end.by E.O.K[endall]. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Ch[arles] B.Trego, May 8, 1855; 11x9; Kongelige Danske videnskabernes selskab
    Copenhagen, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: G.Forchhammer. 1p.,end.by LeC[onte]. In Danish. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, May 8, 1855; 11x9; Königlich Bayerische Akademie der Wissenschaften
    Munich, Printed L. filled in in ms. S.: Wiedmann. 1p., end. by E.O.K[endall]. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, May 10, 1855; 5 1/8" x 8 1/16"; Gilliss, J. M. (James Melville), 1811-1865
    Washington, 1 p. A.L.S. Would like to obtain a copy or copies of G. A. Jahn's article on eclipses, published in 1849.
  - Report of the committee of the Board of Officers on the address of the President, and the subject of re-engraving the seal of the Society, May 11, 1855; 8 1/4" x 12 7/8"; American Philosophical Society. Board of officers
    [Philadelphia], 3 pp. and endorsement. D.S.; John F. Frazer, Cha[rle]s B. Trego.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 16, 1855; 11x9; Regio Istituto veneto di scienze, lettere ed arti (Venice, Italy)
    Philadelphia, Venice, L.S.: Poli. 2p.,end.by E.O.K[endall], and add. In Italian. Wishes to exchange publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, May 18, 1855; 9-1/2x6; Königlich Sächsische Gesellschaft der Wissenschaften zu Leipzig
    Leipzig, Printed L.filled in in ms. S.: E.H.Weber. 1p.,end. by LeC[onte]. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, May 18/30, 1855; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Russia. Observatoire physique central
    St. Petersburg, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: A.Kupffer. 1p.,end.: J.L.LeC[onte]. In French. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to the President of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, May 31, 1855; 11x8; Kungl. Svenska vetenskapsakademien
    Stockholm, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: P.F.Wahlberg. 1p.,end. by LeC[onte]. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the [American] Philosoph[ica]l Society, June 1, 1855; 4 7/8" x 7 13/16"; Miller, John
    London, 1p. A.L.S. Forwards a box of books to the A.P.S. in care of the department of state.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, June 2, 1855; 10x8; Royal Geographical Society (Great Britain)
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Norton Shaw. 1p.,end. by Lec[onte]. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to Ch[arles] B. Trego, June 4, 1855; 10 3/4x8-1/2; Kongelige Danske videnskabernes selskab
    Copenhagen, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Forchhammer 1p.,end.: LeC[onte]. In Danish. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to Ch[arle]s B. Trego, June 4, 1855; 8x5; Shurtleff, Nathaniel Bradstreet, 1810-1874
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p.,end.by J.L.LeC[onte]. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Ch[arles] B. Trego, Philadelphia, June 5, 1855; 12-1/2x8; Bataviaasche genootschap von kunsten en wetenschappen
    Amsterdam, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W. Vrolik. 1p.,end.by E.O.K[endall]. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, Philadelphia, June 8, 1855; 6x7-1/2; New Jersey Historical Society
    Newark, A.L.S.: Sam[ue]l H. Congar. 1p. ,end.: J.L.LeC[onte]. Thanks for APS Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 9, 1855; 9-3/4x7-3/4; American Antiquarian Society
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, June 9, 1855; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Connecticut Historical Society
    Hartford, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Chas. Hosmer. 1p.,end.: E.O.K[endall]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, June 9, 1855; 4 3/8" x 7 1/8"; Darlington, William, 1782-1863
    Secretary of A.P.S., West Chester, 1p. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of A.P.S. proceedings, VI, no.53, containing his obituary notice of William H. Dillingham. Requests half a dozen extra copies.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Philadelphia, June 9, 1855; 9-3/4x8; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: James Walker, pres.and Thaddeus William Harris, Libn. 1p.,end.: E.O.K[endall] and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 11, 1855; 10x8; Rhode Island Historical Society
    Providence, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Albert G. Greene, Pres.and Henry T. Beekwith, Sec. 1p.,end.: J.L.LeC[onte] Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, June 15, 1855; 10x7-3/4; Historical Society of Pennsylvania
    Philadelphia, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Townsend Ward. 1p.,end.: E.O.K[endall]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 16, 1855; 10x8; New York State Library
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 22, 1855; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Boston Society of Natural History
    Boston, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: S.L.Abbott. 1p.,end.: E.O.K[enda11]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], July 4, 1855; 10x7-1/2; Fürstlich Jablonowski'sche Gesellschaft zu Leipzig
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.Hankel 1p.,end.by E.O.K[endall]. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, July 4, 1855; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.Y.Akerman and Edwin Ireland. 2p.,end.by LeC[onte]. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the president of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, July 6, 1855; 10x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington, Printed L.filled in in m.sS.: W.Hunter. 1p.,end. by E.O.K[endall]. Forwards volumes.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, July 25, 1855; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Ethnological Society of London
    A.L.S.: Richard Cull. 2p.,end.by LeC[onte Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the President of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 1/13, 1855; 10x8-1/2; Moskovskoe obshchestvo li︠u︡biteleĭ prirody
    Moscow, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Renard. 1p.,end.by J.L.LeC[onte]. In French. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to President of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 9, 1855; 10x8; Chevalier, Michel, 1806-1879
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p.,end.by C.B.T[rego]. In French. Donates publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 12, 1855; 9x5-1/2; Kongelige Nordiske oldskriftselskab (Denmark)
    Copenhagen, Printed L.filled in in ms.s.: Chas.C.Rafn. 3p.,end.by E.O.K[endall]. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Aug. 15, 1855; 10x8-1/2; Der Naturhistorische verein der Preussischen Rheinlande und Westphalen's.
    Bonn, L.S.: Pudey(?). 1p.,end.by E.O.K[endall]. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 23, 1855; 11x8-1/2; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed L.filled in in ms. S.: Trendelenburg. 1p.,end. by J. L. Lec[onte]. In German. Forwards publications and lists volumes received from the APS.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Sept. 1, 1855; 9-3/4x8; Natural History Society of Northumberland, Durham, & Newcastle-upon-Tyne
    Newcastle, L.S.: Edward Charlton and Joseph Blacklock. 1p.,end.: E.O.K[endall]. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Philadelphia, Sept. 3, 1855; 10x8; Leeds Philosophical & Literary Society
    Leeds, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: George Shaw 1p.,end.: F.F[raley] and add. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 15, 1855; 10x8; Bowditch Library
    Boston, A.L.S.: Henry I. Bowditch. 1p.,end.: F[raley]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Sept. 23, 1855; 11-1/2x9; Kaiserlich-Königliche Geographische Gesellschaft (Austria)
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.Haidinger. 1p.,end.by J.L.LeC[onte]. In German. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to Ch[arle]s B. Trego, September 26, 1855; 5 1/16" x 8 1/16"; Draper, Lyman Copeland, 1815-1891
    Madison, Wisconsin, 2 pp. A.L.S. Regarding books and pamphlets to be forwarded from the State Historical Society of Wisconsin.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct. 1, 1855; 11x8-1/2; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wilhelm Braumüller. 1p.,end.by J.B.LeC[onte]. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to A[lexander] D. Bache, Oct. 11, 1855; 10-1/4x8; Statistical Society (Great Britain)
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edwd.Tudor Scargill. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct. 11, 1855; 9-3/4x8; Zoological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: D.W.Mitchell. 1p.,end.: E.O.K[endall]. Thanks for the Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct. 17, 1855; 12-3/4x8; Royal Society of Arts (Great Britain)
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: C.Le Neve Foster. 1p.,end.: E.O.K[endall] and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American Philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct. 17, 1855; 9x7-1/2; Zoological Society of London
    London Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: D.W.Mitchell. 1p.,end.by F.F[isher]. Forwarded publications through Henry Stevens.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct. 23, 1855; 9x7-1/4; Bath and West and Southern Counties Society
    Bath, L.S.: H.St.John Maule. 2p.,end.: J.L. LeC[onte]. Thanks for publications and forwards their publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 27, 1855; 9-3/4x8; Natural History Society of Northumberland, Durham, & Newcastle-upon-Tyne
    Newcastle, L.S.: Edward Charlton and Joseph Blacklock. 1p.,end.: J.L.LeC[onte],and add. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings.
  - Letter to Ch[arle]s B. Trego, October 30, 1855; 4" x 6 5/16"; Draper, Lyman Copeland, 1815-1891
    Madison, Wisconsin, 2pp. A.L.S. The corresponding secretary of the State Historical Society of Wisconsin requests an exchange of publications with A.P.S.
  - Letter to Peter Lesley, October, 1855; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.)
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 1, 1855; 11x8-1/2; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 9, 1855; 10x8; Linnean Society of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John J. Bennett. 1p.,end.: [J.L.]LeC[onte]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Report of the committee appointed on the Society's seal, November 16, 1855; 7 5/8" x 9 3/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Franklin Bache, F[rederick] Fraley, Franklin Peale. "The Committee deem it inexpedient to have the seal re-engraved at present... "
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 17, 1855; 10x8; Royal Asiatic Society of Great Britain and Ireland
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S: R.Clarke. 1p.,end.: J.L.LeC[onte]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 20, 1855; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.Y.Akerman. 1p.,end.: Lec[onte]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 22, 1855; 14-1/2x9-1/2; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J[oseph] Prestwick. 1p.,end.: J.L.LeC[onte] Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 24, 1855; 9-1/4x6; Königlich Sächsische Gesellschaft der Wissenschaften zu Leipzig
    Leipzig, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: E.H.Weber. 1p.and add. In German. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 7, 1855; 10-1/4x8; Literary and Philosophical Society of Manchester
    [read] Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Robt.Angus Smith. 1p.,end.: E.O.K[endall] and add. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 21, 1855; 10-1/4x8; Literary and Philosophical Society of Manchester
    [read] Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Robt.Angus Smith and E. Schunck. 1p.,end.: J.L.Le C[onte], and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 30, 1855; 11x8-1/2; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    Vienna, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: Wilhelm Braumüller. 1p., end. by J.L. LeC[onte]. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], Dec., 1855; 11x9; Hammer-Purgstall, Joseph, Frieherr von, 1774-1856
    Vienna, L.S. 1p.,end.by C.B.T[rego]. Thanks for publications and forwards publication. FILM403 FRAME115
  - Subscription for the benefit of John Lewis, 1855; American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 12, 1856; 11x9; Königlich Bayerische Akademie der Wissenschaften
    Munich, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wiedmann. 2p.,end.: J.L.LeC[onte]. In German. Thanks for Proceedings. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Ch[arles] B. Trego, Philadelphia, Jan. 15, 1856; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Bataviaasche genootschap von kunsten en wetenschappen
    Amsterdam, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.Vrolik. 1p.,end.: J.L.LeC[onte] and add. In French. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 25, 1856; 10x7-3/4; Historical Society of Pennsylvania
    Philadelphia, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Townsend Ward. 1p.,end.: LeC[onte]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, January 30, 1856; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Ives, William
    Buffalo, 1 p. A.L.S. The librarian of the Young Men's Association orders designated volumes of the A.P.S. Transactions.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Jan. 31, 1856; 10x7-3/4; Pennsylvania. State Library
    Harrisburg, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wm. R. Dewitt. 1p., end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], Jan., 1856; 10-1/2x8; Bossange, firm, booksellers, Paris (1860. Hector Bossange et fils)
    Paris, Printed L. 1p.,end.by E.O.K[endall]. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 1, 1856; 9-3/4x7-3/4; American Antiquarian Society
    Worcester, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: sam[ue]l F. Haven. 1p.,end.: C.B.T.[rego]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 2, 1856; 10x8; Boston Athenaeum
    Boston, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: Thos. G.Cary, Pres.and Charles Folsom, Libn. 1p.,end.: J.L. LeC[onte]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Feb. 2, 1856; 10x8; New Jersey Historical Society
    Newark, A.L.S.: Samuel H. Congar. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 5, 1856; 10x8; Yale University
    New Haven, L.S.: Theodore D. Woolsey, Pres.and Edward C. Herrick, Libn. 1p.,end.: C.B. T[rego]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, Feb. 6, 1856; 10x7-1/2; Connecticut Historical Society
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Feb. 8, 1856; 14x8-1/2; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, A.L.S.: Karl Koch. 1p.,end.: J.L. LeC[onte] and add. In German. Thanks for Proceedings. Forwards publication through the Smithsonian.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 10, 1856; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Joseph Henry. 1p.,end.: J.L.LeC[onte]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, February 11, 1856; 8 1/4" x 10 1/8"; Ives, William
    Buffalo, A.L.S. The librarian of the Young Men's Association acknowledges receipt of A.P.S. Transactions and encloses draft for the same.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred a paper by Dr. J[ohn] L. LeConte, February 15, 1856; 8 1/2" x 10"; American Philosophical Society
    entitled "Revision of the Cicindelae of the United States," [Philadelphia], 1 p. D.S.: S[amuel] S. Haldeman, Robert Bridges. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to Thomas [sic] B. Trego, Feb. 27, 1856; 7-1/2x5; Swallow, G. C. (George Clinton), 1817-1899
    Columbia, Mo., A.L.S. 1p.,end.by C.B.T[rego]. Forwards geological reports of Missouri.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, March 8, 1856; 10-1/2x8-1/4
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.H.Smyth. 1p.,end.: J.L.LeC[onte] and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 20, 1856; 9-3/4x7-3/4; New York Academy of Sciences
    New York, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John H. Redfield. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, April 1, 1856; 5" x 8"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, 1 p. A.L.S. Regarding inquiry of Professor Snell of Amherst concerning back issues of A.P.S. Proceedings.
  - Letter to ----, April 3, 1856; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Ramsey, Samuel
    Washington, 2 pp. A.L.S. Wishes to know where the original Declaration of Independence is located; also provenance of copy in possession of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, April 4, 1856; 8x6-1/2; Finley, Clement A. (Clement Alexander), 1797-1879
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, April 5, 1856; 8" x 10"; Short, Charles Wilkins, 1794-1863
    Secretary of A.P.S., Louisville, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Reasons for his failure to prepare a biographical memoir of his uncle, Mr. William Short. See Pro., VI, 185.
  - Letter to ----, April 10, 1856; 6" x 7 1/4"; Brown, D.
    Byhalia, Miss., 1 p. A.L.S. Requests that a few specimen numbers of A.P.S. Transactions be sent to him, as he wishes to subscribe to the same.